TUFAIL AHMAD MIR

CONTACT

fateh kadal, baba demb, srinagar, jammu and kashmir 190002 india

+917006919907

SKILLS

- Typescript/ javascript
- Android. (Hybrid)
- Ios. (Hybrid)
- React React Native
- Redux Tailwind Git PullState
- Nextjs HTML/CSS AntDesign
- Github Typescript
- Jest/React-testing-library / cypress
- Rxjs
- Nextjs 13.5

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an experienced General Purpose Developer with specialisation in web technologies who employs the most recent and most effective technologies. My passion is to provide my clients with clean, modern, responsive and fully validated products using latest proven technologies. Over the last 3 years, I have implemented different design architectures from scratch and also designed/redesigned many websites and applications for numerous businesses using many different frameworks and technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Aurodigital | miami, south florida, UNITED STATES

• February 2023 - July 2023

Frontend lead

As a Senior Frontend Developer and Team Lead, I had the privilege of spearheading a team of three talented junior developers to create a cutting-edge Aggregated Exchange SaaS (Software as a Service) platform tailored for institutional-level clients. This role required a deep understanding of frontend development, leadership skills, and the ability to optimize performance for real-time ordering of digital assets.

MoEVing | delhi, delhi, india

August 2022 - February 2023

Software Engineer

- MoEVing
- A Product based company working on EV vehicles with their own charging stations
- Here I developed 2 products for moeving
- Developed an admin web-app for performing CRUD operations on entrepreneurs and drivers associated with moeving and creating ledgers or generating payslips etc
- Build an Android mobile app for entrepreneurs to operate orders for vehicles and drivers, Metafic is an award-winning agile software & technology development company that works on ambitious projects with visionary clients from all across the globe

Metafic | singapore

March 2022 - August 2022

Front End Developer

- Driven by strategy, design, and passion, we work on end-to-end solutions for mobile apps, web, XR, eCommerce, and softwaresBuild
- an Android mobile app which deals with advertising 24/7 on tabs fitted inside the cab
- Developed a web-app for 'four seasons Beverly hills' for operating there luxury car providing services for clients staying in the hotelsAnother web-app for the clients to book the cars
- Worked on e-learning platform also ,Refactored it's code and changed its patterns to DRY approach of react

Graphicweave | srinagar, jammu and kashmir

January 2021 - February 2022

Front End Developer

Designing and implementing the front-end using HTML5, CSS3, jQueryReactJS

- Preparing multiple designs and wireframes for clients approval before proceeding with development
- PROJECTS BusyBee-Vendor-Mobile-App(ios/android)
- BusyBee is a platform where vendors can connect directly to organisatons, place orders and
 enquiries, so you are not overly dependent on your sales agentsWorked primarily as the Front End
 Developer for this appMobile app prototype conversion to working screens using React-nativeUsed
 Component based approach for code reusabilityUsed Shopify Restyles for building UI upon a design
 systemUsed Pull-State for global state management instead of using redux's large setup and not
 overkilling the code with a large intial setup required in ReduxUnilife
- https://vendor.unilife.in A student centric platform of its kind and will host the largest student community in IndiaIt will help empower students with greater purchasing potentialWorked primarily

as the Front End Developer for the Unilife Vendor Panel inReact.JSUsed Component

EDUCATION

December 2022

Bachelor of Computer Applications
Islamia college of Science and Commerce

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Everywhereagents 1:- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.everywhereagents
- Everywhereagents 2- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.everywhereagents.orion
- Unilife :- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.crewdewtech.unilife